迷住我。简化我的生活。让我惊喜。
Enchant me. Simplify my life. Make me amazing. They're
这些都是令人不敢相信的单方面结婚誓言，同时也是
incredibly one-sided wedding vows, and the three key principles
Android团队对这个平台和其上运行的app们
underlying the Android team's creative vision for the platform
Android team
赋予的创意愿景的三大关键原则。
and the apps that run on it. As engineers,
作为工程师，人们有时很难看到
it can sometimes be difficult to see past our
我们驾驭sdk的力量
own delight at harnessing the power of an sdk
驯服机器让其如我所愿时的那种喜悦，但最终，
to bend a machine to our will, but ultimately,
我们的目标必须是为我们的用户
our goal must be to create that same empowering experience
创造同样的感受。于是我们通过创造
for our users. And we do that by creating apps
美丽悦人，同时又强大而好用的app来做到这一点。
that are as esthetically pleasing as they are functional and
用户在最开始的三十秒内
easy to use. Users judge the quality of your app
就会对你的app产生评价。 这可能不公平，
within the first 30 seconds. It may not be fair,
但是不成比例的这种评价将会不仅
but a disproportionate amount of that judgement will be based
基于功能，而是基于视觉美感。
not on the functionality, but on the visual aesthetics. Does
看起来有没有打磨过？看起来是否专业？
it look polished? Does it look professional? How easy is
有多容易用？不仅要看起来美美哒，整个
it to use? More than just looking pretty, the entire user
用户体验更是至关重要。因为只有30秒来户
experience is critically important. With 30 seconds to
争取用户，着陆过程变得尤为关键。
win users over, it's critical that that onboarding process
从下载到打开你的app以显示其主要功能的过程
the time and effort required to go from downloading
所需要的时间和精力应当
your app to performing it's main function should be
尽可能的简短顺滑。
as short and frictionless as possible. Not only
不止如此，一个精心设计的app应当
that, but a well designed app should evoke a
激发潜意识的本能反应。
visceral reaction that speaks to the subconscious. It should
他应该用起来很有趣。他应当以令人愉悦的方式给予惊喜
be fun to use. It should surprise in delightful
来个小动画或者顺滑的渐变
ways through subtle animations and smooth transitions that contribute
这些都会带来强大且轻而易举的感受。
to a feeling of power and effortlessness. It should
让用户直接与物件接触交互
let users touch and interact with objects directly rather
而非不得不使用按钮和菜单。
than having to use buttons and menus. And it should
使用丰富的隐喻和图片来替代
use rich imagery and pictures in place of lots
过多的文字和长居。提供漂亮而敏感的默认项，使得用户
of words and long sentences. It allows users to
可以个性化你的app，使之变成他们自己的。
customize your app, to make it theirs while providing
创造一些如同魔法一般的东西，
beautiful and sensible defaults. Create something that works like magic,
从设备提供的上下文习得你的偏好
learning your preference in the context provided by
于是就再也不用征询用户那些他们
the device so it never asks users for information
已经提供的信息。提供简单的快捷方式来完成
that they've already provided. Provide simple shortcuts to complete
复杂的任务，并且记住数据设置和个人定制
complex tasks, and remember data settings and customizations making
使他们可以跨设备可用。创建一个亲切并且受欢迎的体验
them available across every device. While it's good practice
是一个很好的实践。你可以通过创建与平台的样式主题相符的
to create a familiar and welcoming experience by creating
外观和感受来达到这一点。
a look and feel that's consistent with the platforms
同时你也要记得
styles and themes, it's just as important to remember
所有我在此讨论过的其他原则
that this, and all the other principles I've discussed
都真的只是你自己创造力的起点。
here, are really just a starting point for your
偏离这份指导方针是不提倡的，
own creative vision. Deviation from the guidelines is encouraged,
但若你真要这么干，那就带着决心偏离吧。
but when you do do so, deviate with purpose.